1134 Irving Street San Francisco, CA 94122 Phone: (801) 709-0238 mathews.kyle@gmail.com https://bricolage.io

### Kyle Mathews

#### Summary

Experienced web developer/designer with a deep knowledge of open source software development, education, and social software.

Passionate about finding elegant solutions to important problems. Experienced entrepreneur. Creative, risk taker, strong writer and communicator, experienced public speaker.

#### Education

Brigham Young University

2009. M.S., Information Systems.

2009. B.S., Information Systems.

#### Experience

Technical co-founder at RelateRocket

June 2014 – June 2016

I co-founded RelateRocket, an enterprise SaaS company. Our product algorithimically generated targeted insights and messaging for sales reps. I led product and engineering and designed and built a robust and scalable data intake and analysis platform. The platform took data from customers CRMs and merged it in real-time with data from multiple 3rd-party information sources. The insights were served to sales reps through a custom Salesforce app built with React.js, Relay, and GraphQL.

Senior Frontend Engineer and Product Manager at Pantheon December 2011 – April 2014

#### Highlights of my time at Pantheon include:

- Rebuilding the Pantheon dashboard from the ground up as a real-time single-page-app using Backbone.js and SockJS.
- Designing and building Multidev cloud development environments for teams. Basically Git for the entire stack (files, DB, and code) not just code. It's been a huge hit for customers with larger teams of developers.
- Designing and building Pantheon One a suite of tools for customers administering 100s to 1000s of websites.

#### Founder at Eduglu

January 2009 – March 2011

I founded Eduglu to productize social learning research I did while in college. Eduglu was one of the first Drupal products to be released. Eduglu was downloaded over 600 times and has been successfully deployed at a number of different institutions including Brigham Young University and Georgia State University.

Skills

## **Product Management**

I led product management at Pantheon for all customer facing features. My bible is The Principles of Product Development Flow: Second Generation Lean Product Development.

# Technologies

**Front end** React.js, Relay, Typography.js, HTML, CSS **Programming languages** Javascript/CoffeeScript, Python, PHP

### Public speaking

I have presented at a number of international education and technology conferences as well as many smaller conferences and meetups including:

<sup>&</sup>quot;Building Advanced Social Networks at a Large U.S. University" Drupalcon DC 2009

<sup>&</sup>quot;Introducing Eduglu, a new Drupal distribution for Higher Education" Teaching
With Technology Idea Exchange 2010

<sup>&</sup>quot;Building Social Networks for Learning" Ignite Salt Lake City 2009